British Columbia Student Federation fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
British Columbia Student Federation fonds
1958 - 1986
F-159
Q106660330
1.5 m of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
British Columbia Student Federation
The British Columbia Assembly of Students (BCAS), formally established in 1966, grew out of a 1965 meeting of delegates from universities, colleges, technical schools, and secondary schools. The students wanted a province-wide forum for the discussion of issues relevant to them.
The BCAS was succeeded in 1969 by the British Columbia Union of Students, which included only university and regional college representatives. This group concentrated on issues such as unemployment, housing, and civil liberties. For example, it established a student employment task force, and produced a lengthy report on the subject.
The BC Union of Students, in turn, was succeeded in 1972 by the British Columbia Association of Student Unions, formed by representatives of 16 student councils across the province. The Association's formal structure was limited; it had no financing, no staff and no central coordination of information. To overcome these limitations, BCASU delegates resolved to restructure the organization. The result was the British Columbia Federation of Students.
In order to join the BCSF, a student organization had to conduct a referendum among its members to join the BCSF on the basis of a per student levy. The BCSF provided a means of communication between different student organizations in order to build support for common interests. An executive met regularly and was advised by a number of committees. As well, the BCSF held semi-annual conferences. The BCSF employed staff members from time to time as well as researchers to collect information on topics such as a dental plan, student housing, daycare, student employment, financial aid, transferability of courses, and the financing of post-secondary institutions.
In 1982, the Simon Fraser Student Society voted to join the Canadian Federation of Students. The BCSF reformed itself as the Canadian Federation of Students---Pacific Region.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on the name of the organization.
The fonds consists of records made or received in the course of administering the BCSF and carrying out its programs. Activities documented include the establishment and organization of the various student groups; executive and general meetings; management of financial resources; research into policy issues; and lobbying activities. Documents include agenda and minutes; constitutions; correspondence; briefs and reports; newsletters; and news clippings.
The original order of the fonds is unknown. The first series was constructed by the archivist to reflect the establishment of three predecessor organizations. The other series were established to reflect activities falling under a similar function and generating related records.
Community life
Unknown.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
Consult the Simon Fraser Student Society fonds, F-74.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Predecessor organizations records, 1960 - 1975; F-159-1; 14 cm of textual records
  published
  Series comprises records made or received by the three predecessor organizations of the BCSF. Includes correspondence, briefs and reports, constitution, and agenda and minutes.
  - British Columbia Assembly of Students, 1960 - 1969; F-159-1-1; 4 cm of textual records
    - Constitution, 1960 - 1969; F-159-1-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-1)
      Textual records
      Open
    - Briefs and reports, 1965 - 1968; F-159-1-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 - 1967; F-159-1-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-1)
  - British Columbia Union of Students, 1968 - 1971; F-159-1-2; 6 cm of textual records
    - Constitution, 1969 - 1970; F-159-1-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-1)
    - Correspondence, 1968 - 1969; F-159-1-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-1)
    - Meeting briefs and reports, 1968 - 1970; F-159-1-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-1)
    - Meeting briefs and reports, 1970 - 1971; F-159-1-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-1)
  - British Columbia Association of Student Unions, 1971 - 1975; F-159-1-3; 5 cm of textual records
    - Agenda and minutes of conferences and meetings, 1971 - 1973; F-159-1-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-1)
    - Agenda and minutes of conferences and meetings, 1974; F-159-1-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-1)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1972 - 1973; F-159-1-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
    - Correspondence, briefs and reports, 1974 - 1975; F-159-1-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
- Administration and organization files, 1971 - 1985; F-159-2; 11 cm of textual records
  Series comprises records made or received by the BCSF in the course of establishing the organization and administering its programs. Activities documented include the creation of the BCSF, its organizational changes over time and evolution into the Canadian Federation of Students---Pacific Region; and management of the organization's finances. Includes correspondence, briefs, reports, financial statements and other documents.
  - Briefs and statements, 1971 - 1981; F-159-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
  - Canadian Federation of Students Education in BC: The 5-Year Plan, 1982; F-159-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
    Pending review
  - Conference - Federal-Provincial First Ministers, 1976; F-159-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
  - Constitution, 1976 - 1981; F-159-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
  - Correspondence - Canadian Federation of Students, Pacific Region, 1982 - 1985; F-159-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
  - Early development and organization notes, 1975 - 1977; F-159-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
  - Executive proposals and reports, 1975 - 1981; F-159-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
  - Financial statements, budgets and reports, 1975 - 1982; F-159-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
  - Fundraising proposal (lottery), 1975; F-159-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
  - Newsletters, 1977 - 1978; F-159-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
  - Organization and restructuring, 1975 - 1982; F-159-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
  - Statistics, 1983; F-159-2-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 159-2)
- Agenda and minutes, 1975 - 1981; F-159-3; 6 cm of textual records
  Series comprises records of the meetings of the BCSF Executive and General Meetings. Includes agenda, minutes, and supporting papers.
  - Executive meetings - Agenda and minutes, 1975 - 1981; F-159-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
  - General meetings - Agenda and minutes, 1975 - 1976; F-159-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
  - General meetings - Agenda and minutes, 1976 - 1977; F-159-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
  - General meetings - Agenda and minutes, 1977 - 1978; F-159-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
  - General meetings - Agenda and minutes, 1979 - 1980; F-159-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
  - General meetings - Agenda and minutes, 1980 - 1981; F-159-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
- Subject files, 1958 - 1986; F-159-4; 95 cm of textual records
  Series comprises records made or received in the course of carrying out research on topics of concern to students. Includes correspondence, reports, briefs, newsletters, news clippings, surveys, press releases, and other documents.
  - Day care services, 1969 - 1981; F-159-4-1; 11 cm of textual records
    - Correspondence - act and regulations, 1969 - 1978; F-159-4-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
      Restricted in part
    - Correspondence - Acadia day care centre, 1969 - 1980; F-159-4-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
    - Correspondence - organization, 1974 - 1975; F-159-4-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
    - Briefs and reports, 1971 - 1980; F-159-4-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
    - Coalitions - BC Daycare Action and Central Okanagan Day Care, 1981; F-159-4-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
    - New Caledonia College, Prince George, 1980 - 1981; F-159-4-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
    - Newsletters - Child Care Federation, 1974; F-159-4-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 159-3)
    - Pacific Vocational Institute - correspondence and reports, 1979 - 1980; F-159-4-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 159-4)
    - Publications and guides, 1970 - 1981; F-159-4-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 159-4)
    - Surveys, correspondence and day of protest, 1979 - 1981; F-159-4-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 159-4)
  - Education, 1972 - 1986; F-159-4-2; 15 cm of textual records
    - BC Association of Colleges - reports for 13th Annual General Meeting, 1980; F-159-4-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-4)
    - Colleges and Provincial Institutes Act - briefs and reports, 1975 - 1984; F-159-4-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-4)
    - Interior education - briefs to Winegard Commission June 26, 1976, F-159-4-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-4)
    - Interior of BC University Degree programs proposals, 1976 - 1980; F-159-4-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-4)
    - Ministry of Education - reports on Education Performance and Facility Planning, 1976 - 1977; F-159-4-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-4)
    - Notre Dame University cutbacks, 1975 - 1986; F-159-4-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 159-4)
    - Occupational training - Manpower cutbacks, 1972 - 1982; F-159-4-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
    - Post Secondary participation and enrolment briefs and statistics, 1979 - 1981; F-159-4-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
    - Teaching assistants and TSSU, 1977 - 1979; F-159-4-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
    - Universities Council of B C - 5th and 6th annual reports, 1979 - 1980; F-159-4-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
    - Vocational and occupational training - briefs and reports, 1976 - 1980; F-159-4-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
    - Vocational and technical training - correspondence, briefs and reports, 1972 - 1982; F-159-4-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
  - Education funding, 1958 - 1984; F-159-4-3; 6 cm of textual records
    - Fees - University of British Columbia tuition, 1958 - 1964; F-159-4-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
    - Budget planning, 1980 - 1984; F-159-4-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
    - Federal financing expenditures, 1970 - 1976; F-159-4-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
    - Fiscal Arrangements Act - briefs, correspondence, reports and conferences, 1975 - 1981; F-159-4-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
    - Reports and recommendations for funding through Government grants, 1978 - 1983; F-159-4-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-5)
  - Employment, 1969 - 1985; F-159-4-4; 13 cm of textual records
    - Briefs and reports re strategies for workshops, 1975 - 1977; F-159-4-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-6)
    - Income Opportunities - report, 1973; F-159-4-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-6)
    - Press releases, 1976 - 1980; F-159-4-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-6)
    - Questionnaire and survey, 1974 - 1977; F-159-4-4-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-6)
    - Statistics, 1975 - 1985; F-159-4-4-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-6)
    - Summer student employment program, 1969 - 1981; F-159-4-4-0-6 (Archival box - standard 159-6)
    - Unemployment - conferences, workshops, 1971 - 1983; F-159-4-4-0-7 (Archival box - standard 159-6)
    - Youth Employment Program - conferences, workshops, 1978 - 1982; F-159-4-4-0-8 (Archival box - standard 159-6)
  - Housing, 1970 - 1984; F-159-4-5; 12 cm of textual records
    - Briefs, reports, workshops, 1975 - 1981; F-159-4-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
    - Campaigns, 1976 - 1981; F-159-4-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
    - Correspondence, 1975 - 1981; F-159-4-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
    - Guides and handbooks, 1975; F-159-4-5-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
    - KJAM Housing Co-op, 1981 - 1984; F-159-4-5-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
    - Off Campus Student Housing Committee - reports, recommendations, minutes and press releases, 1974 - 1981; F-159-4-5-0-6 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
    - Residences - establishment, standards and policy, 1979 - 1980; F-159-4-5-0-7 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
    - Correspondence and Report -Student Housing in Post Secondary Education Chapter 1 Summary and Recommendations Chapter 2 The Numerical Base; The Financial Base, Joseph Powadiuk, 1970 - 1971; F-159-4-5-0-8 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
    - Report - Student Housing in Post Secondary Education - Chapter 3 The Statistical Base, Joseph Powadiuk, 1971; F-159-4-5-0-9 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
    - Report - Student Housing in Post Secondary Education Appendices and Bibliography, Joseph Powadiuk, 1971; F-159-4-5-0-10 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
    - Universities Council of BC - reports, 1977 - 1980; F-159-4-5-0-11 (Archival box - standard 159-7)
  - Student affairs, 1973 - 1985; F-159-4-6; 7 cm of textual records
    - Accessibility - correspondence and reports, 1977 - 1985; F-159-4-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-8)
    - Activism - correspondence and reports, 1978 - 1984; F-159-4-6-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-8)
    - Newsletter - Federated Anti-Poverty Groups of BC, 1978 - 1979; F-159-4-6-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-8)
    - Student Unions / Societies - organization and management briefs, reports and workshops, 1975 - 1979; F-159-4-6-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-8)
    - Transit fares and services - correspondence, briefs, reports and press clippings, 1973 - 1985; F-159-4-6-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-8)
  - Student financing, 1973 - 1985; F-159-4-7; 12 cm of textual records
    - Cutback campaigns - correspondence and organization, 1978 - 1979; F-159-4-7-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-8)
    - Cutbacks - briefs, reports and workshops, 1975 - 1981; F-159-4-7-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-8)
    - Fee structure - reports and statistics, 1975 - 1980; F-159-4-7-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-8)
    - Financial Aid - reports and recommendations, 1973 - 1975; F-159-4-7-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-8)
    - Financial Aid - briefs and reports, 1976 - 1977; F-159-4-7-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-8)
    - Financial Aid - correspondence, briefs and reports, 1978 - 1979; F-159-4-7-0-6 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
    - Financial Aid - correspondence, briefs and reports, 1980 - 1981; F-159-4-7-0-7 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
    - "Student Saver" Program, 1985; F-159-4-7-0-8 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
    - "Student Saver Program" - sponsor list, F-159-4-7-0-9 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
    - Tuition fees - correspondence, briefs, reports and workshops, 1976 - 1985; F-159-4-7-0-10 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
  - Student rights, 1975 - 1981; F-159-4-8; 7 cm of textual records
    - Bilingualism in Education, 1977 - 1979; F-159-4-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
    - Briefs and reports - drafts, 1975 - 1981; F-159-4-8-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
    - Correspondence, 1980 - 1981; F-159-4-8-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
    - First Nations students -reports and workshops, 1977 - 1981; F-159-4-8-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
    - International students - admissions and enrolment reports and statistics, 1975 - 1980; F-159-4-8-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
    - Ombudsperson - questionnaire, press releases, reports, terms of reference and seminars, 1977 - 1978; F-159-4-8-0-6 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
    - Student Bills of Rights - drafts, 1980 - 1981; F-159-4-8-0-7 (Archival box - standard 159-9)
  - Student services, 1977 - 1982; F-159-4-9; 7 cm of textual records
    - Advisory Committee - agenda and minutes, 1977 - 1980; F-159-4-9-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-10)
    - Advisory Committee - correspondence, 1977 - 1982; F-159-4-9-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-10)
    - Advisory Committee - workshop, 1978; F-159-4-9-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-10)
    - Conference, 1980 - 1981; F-159-4-9-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-10)
    - Model for Student Services in BC, 1978 - 1981; F-159-4-9-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-10)
  - Press clippings, 1971 - 1982; F-159-4-10; 7 cm of textual records
    - Briefs, correspondence and reports - committee, conference and workshops, 1975 - 1982; F-159-4-10-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-10)
    - Correspondence, 1980 - 1982; F-159-4-10-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-10)
    - Gaining status and women's rights, 1972 - 1982; F-159-4-10-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-10)
    - Guides, handbooks and publications, 1971 - 1982; F-159-4-10-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-10)
    - Resource Kits, 1980 - 1981; F-159-4-10-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-10)
- Press clippings, 1974 - 1985; F-159-5; 26 cm of textual records
  Series consists of press clippings about student-related issues as collected by the BCSF.
  - Press Clippings: various subjects and undated, 1975 - 1984; F-159-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: (Scrapbook), 1975 - 1981; F-159-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: (Scrapbook) 1/2, 1981; F-159-5-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: (Scrapbook) 2/2, 1981; F-159-5-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: (Scrapbook), 1981 - 1985; F-159-5-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: Activism, 1984 - 1985; F-159-5-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: Day Care, 1976 - 1981; F-159-5-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: Employment, 1975 - 1980; F-159-5-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: Employment, 1981 - 1985; F-159-5-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: Established Program Financing, 1980; F-159-5-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: Financial Aid, 1975; F-159-5-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: First Nations Issues, 1976 - 1981; F-159-5-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: Housing, 1974 - 1981; F-159-5-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 159-11)
  - Press Clippings: International Students, 1975 - 1983; F-159-5-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 159-12)
  - Press Clippings: Post Secondary Education Funding, 1976 - 1984; F-159-5-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 159-12)
  - Press Clippings: Public Schools, 1976 - 1983; F-159-5-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 159-12)
  - Press Clippings: Social Services, 1976 - 1982; F-159-5-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 159-12)
  - Press Clippings: Teaching Assistants, 1978 - 1980; F-159-5-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 159-12)
  - Press Clippings: Tuition Fees, 1977 - 1982; F-159-5-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 159-12)
  - Press Clippings: Transit, 1978; F-159-5-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 159-12)
  - Press Clippings: Women's Issues, 1976 - 1982; F-159-5-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 159-12)